RILESH PATTERI

Cell: +91 8879312532 rileshpatteri@gmail.com

SUMMARY

To work in a progressive organization where I can enhance my skills and learning to contribute to the success of the organization. 5 years of EOD running and support experience of FCC and FCR Softwares.*A FlexCube Functional Expert with more than 5 years of hands on experience in Oracle Financial Software Solutions (i-flex Solutions) FLEXCUBE RETAIL (FCR Version 6.2 & FCR Version 11.6). *Experience in RTGS AND NEFT Transactions Monitoring and Support. *Extensive experience in post implementation and support of FCR application Versions 6.2 and 11.6. *Handling of MIS reports and other banking reports. *Hands on experience in application and database patch implementation in UAT and production setup and testing. *Knowledge in SQL query & PL/SQL language.

SKILLS

• Concepts: Banking Fundamentals,FCR,RTGS,NEFT,EOD/BOD,Operating System, Networking & Database.

• Banking

Modules:CASA,TD,CLEARING,PAYMENTS,CHARGES.

• Operating System: Windows XP,WIN-2K,WIN-,2K3,WIN-7,UNIX,LINUX & AIX systems.

• Database Language : SQL,PL/SQL.

 Database Tools: PL/SQL Developer, TOAD, SQL Navigator

• Testing Tools : Manual Testing

• Database : Oracle

WORK EXPERIENCE

WIPRO INFOTECH

Mumbai

Senior Application Support Engineer

08/2014 to Current

- Providing Techno Functional Support to Our Layer 1 Application Support Team members.
- Providing 1st level telephonic support during EOD shells aborts, hung and run long time.
- Providing support in sql query preparation to L1 team for providing various data to different department.
- Providing any audit related, Demonetization related and other MIS Report which needs to submit RBI to bank officials.
- Providing Clarification/advice and Temporary and Permanent Solution to queries raised by Different Departments Bank officials.
- For any system bug or Issue, raising the issues with Vendor and the fix provided by Vendor gets tested in UAT with the help of Testing team. Then raising RFC with fix and POA and presenting it in CAB meeting and gets the RFC approved and the changes gets applied in system coordination with Database and Release management team.
- Once in a week will perform consistency check in CASA and TD accounts for any balance mismatch and also do the checks for other system bugs.
- Monitoring GLs on daily/Monthly basis and providing Rectification entries to OPS team with necessary Approval and Remarks.
- Performing Bank level maintenance like Clearing Holiday, NEFT/RTGS Holiday and cutoff, Saving, TD Slab and Rate maintenance, FCNR and RFC deposit rate maintenance. Always verifying rates are applied properly post effective date EOD and providing report to Product team.
- Performing Activities like New Branch Setup, New CASA/TD product creation and modification and other
 parameter maintenance like Endpoint Creation, DD Branches, MICR & Routing code, Currency Codes, Sector
 Codes, UDF and CBR fiels, Picklist, Cards, etc..
- Post Month end release performing Monthly statement and Combined statement process and doing consistency check on statement report tables and handover to E statement team and Vendor for Statement printing.
- Post Monthend Release Manually calculating AMB/AQB charges, AMB based Cash Deposit Charges and IMPS
 charges for the month/Quarter for whole Active and Applicable accounts and applying the charges through gefu by
 OPS team post verification and approval from product team.

WIPRO INFOTECH LTD

Mumbai

Application Support Engineer

- 07/2012 to 08/2014
- Day-to-day production support queries raised by more than 1000 Branches 3 NOCs.
- Solving branch users' queries of FCR application on daily basis, Playing Techno functional roll. On basis of functionality FCR Modules supported are: CASA,TD,CLEARING,PAYMENTS AND CHARGES.
- Preparing various Daily/monthly MIS report and publishing to different Departments.
- Deployment of vendor provided units and database patches first in UAT and if tested OK then deployed in PRODUCTION setup.
- Co-ordination with Network team and database team to resolve the queries related to link or database related Problems

WIPRO INFOTECH

Mumbai

Data center Operation

09/2007 to 07/2012

- EOD and BOD of IFLEX core banking solutions- FCC (Flex Cube Corporate) and FCR (Flex Cube Retail), MUREX Treasury Banking Application, Retail Asset (Finn One, LMS, FAS etc), CASHIN (Collection and Disbursement), RBI applications viz. RTGS PI, SFMS, NEFT, CFMS, PDO NDS and CCIL Applications.
- EOD aborts and Escalation handling.
- Deployment of Patches/units in various banking applications Production servers and databases.
- RMAN, ARCHIVE, MKSYS and export and tape backup of AIX and windows servers and dbs as per daily, weekly and monthly schedule.
- Housekeeping activities on a windows and AIX systems on daily, weekly, bi-monthly, monthly and quarterly schedule after completion of respective tape backups.
- Operation activities like Importing and Exporting backup of tables, Indexing and Analyzing of different db schemas, and database Startup and Shutdown operation as per the weekly or monthly schedules.
- Preparation and maintenance of MIS reports for audit purpose. Documentation of Operational Manuals and EOD/BOD/BACKUPS checklists.
- Site Induction for new joiners'.

ACCEL FRONTLINE LTD

Customer support Engineer

09/2005 to 09/2007

- Performance of CSOLOP, CEOD, CBOD and ISOLOP of Finacle Core Banking application.
- EOD/BOD and IT support of RBI Applications like RTGS, PDO-NDS, CFMS and CCIL application.
- Daily file transfer activity, services restart and logs backup of live servers

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA: DIPLOMA IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Jun-2005

Government Polytechnic collage, Kannur, Kerala, India

Electrical Engineering Department of Technical Education Kerala in with 74.5% of marks.

ASSOCIATE OF SCIENCE: H.S.C,SCIENCE

2002

IMNGHSS SCHOOL, Kannur, Kerala, India

Passed H.S.C. from Board of Public Examination Kerala in Mar – 2002 with 63% of marks.

- IBM Certified Specialist System p Administration.
- Certified on Introduction to Oracle 9i: SQL.(Certificate No- OC0951618).
- Participated in 20 days Training Program on "Basics of IT hardware and Network & Unix system" conducted by ACCEL IT ACADAMY, Kochi-Kerala.
- Participated in 3 days Training Program on "Oracle 11g Database Administration" conducted by Wipro InfoTech, Mumbai.
- Completed Certification Training course on "Basics of Windows system" conducted by CMS Institute in Vashi,
 Mumbai
- Completed Certification Training course on "Linux Administration" conducted by Rajeev Banerji in Vashi, Mumbai.
- Completed Certification Training course on "PL/SQL Introduction to Oracle 9i" conducted by NIIT in Vashi, Mumbai.

- PRESENTATION

PERSONAL INFORMATION —
$Date\ of\ Birth: 21-Feb-1984\ Sex: Male\ Passport\ No: K1518725\ Languages\ Known: English, Hindi,\ Malayalam,\ Tamil\ and\ Marathi\ Nationality: Indian$
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION —

• Personal Profile: Date of Birth : 21-Feb-1984 Sex : Male Passport No : K1518725 Languages Known : English, Hindi, Malayalam and Tamil Nationality : Indian